回到自然的感觉真好
It's nice to get back to nature.
我应该多出来看看
Why don't I do this more often?
这个森林好美啊
What a beautiful forest.
你好啊 小蝴蝶
Hello, little butterfly.
你叫什么...
What's your na...
你在干什么呢?
Whatcha doing?
我在享受虚拟现实呢
I was enjoying some virtual reality,
而你真实的脸把这一切都毁了
until you ruined it with your actual face.
这是什么味道?
What am I smelling?
这是空气清新剂
Oh, it's car air freshener.
我在模拟森林的气味
I was simulating the smell of the forest.
森林可不是这个味道
That's not what the forest smells like.
我怎么知道?
Well, how would I know?
你干嘛要假装自己在外出啊?
Why are you pretending to be outdoors?
你又不喜欢
You hate it.
Amy给我看了一份研究报告
Amy showed me a compelling study
上面说待在野外
that demonstrated the cognitive benefit
对认知能力有好处
of spending time in the wilderness.
哥们 你要是愿意
Buddy, I am ready to drive you
我随时开车送你去野外
into the wilderness any time you want
然后把你丢在那里
and leave you there.
你开玩笑好了 但是有一些受试者
Well, make your jokes, but some of the participants
在森林里过了四天没有现代科技的生活
who spent four days in the woods away from all technology
回来的时候发现自己的推理能力增强了百分之五十
reported a 50% gain in reasoning skills upon their return.
要是那是真的 这个世界上怎么没有天才松鼠呢?
Okay, if that's true, why aren't there more genius squirrels?
我看你比我更需要这个
You may need this more than I do.
* 宇宙一度又烫又稠密 *
* Our whole universe was in a hot, dense state *
* 140亿年前终于爆了炸... 等着瞧! *
* Then nearly 14 billion years ago expansion started... Wait! *
* 地球开始降温 *
* The Earth began to cool *
* 自养生物来起哄 穴居人发明工具 *
* The autotrophs began to drool, Neanderthals developed tools *
* 我们建长城 我们建金字塔 *
* We built the Wall * * We built the pyramids *
* 数学 自然科学 历史 揭开神秘 *
* Math, Science, History, unraveling the mystery *
* 一切由大爆炸开始 *
* That all started with a big bang *
生活大爆炸 第九季第20集
--==圣城家园SCG字幕组 http://hdscg.com/==--
仅供翻译交流使用, 禁止用于商业用途
协调: 酥酥爱喷喷
校对: UUUUUU
翻译: 小黄不小黄 無限月讀
翻译: AU薇 李小宝Licht
你的茶
Here's your tea.
哦!
Oh!
人家正坐在木头上呢 别偷偷摸摸吓人家啊
Do not sneak up on a guy when he's sitting on a log.
你要是真的想去看大自然的话
You know, if you really want to be in nature,
要不我们租一间林中小屋吧?
why don't we rent a cabin?
不好意思啊 你到底是什么时候来的啊? 我...
Look, I'm sorry, when did you even get here? I...
有一个跟我合作的医生
You know, there's a cabin in Big Bear
一直让我去住一间在大熊区的小屋
that a doctor I work with keeps offering me.
他是想追你吧?
Because he's hitting on you?
是个女的
She.
好吧
Oh, good.
但是我绝对能撩动她
But I could get her.
我们周末可以一起去啊
We could all go for the weekend.
肯定很好玩的
It'll be fun.
好吧... 你等等
Yeah... Excuse me.
给你 查一下"好玩"是什么意思再来找我
Here, look up "fun," get back to me.
我们还是可以去过一个周末的啊
You and I could still go and have a nice weekend.
好啊
Sure.
Sheldon啊 我们和他们一起去吧
Come on, Sheldon, let's go with them.
绝对不行
I hardly think so.
你别忘了
You be sure and say hello
和那些蚊子 蜜蜂 熊 蛇
to all the mosquitoes, bees, bears, snakes,
负鼠和毒漆树打招呼啊
possums, poison oak,
哦 还没完呢 还有小年轻弹吉他
oh, and last, but not least, teenagers with guitars.
我问问看那个房子空不空
I'll see if it's available.
如果那个研究是正确的话
You know, if that study's real,
Leonard回来的时候说不定会比你更聪明呢
Leonard might come back smarter than you.
- 你是想摆布我吗?  - 是的
- Are you trying to manipulate me?  - Yes.
干得好 你成功了 我们走
Well done, it worked, we're going.
好!
Yay!
拜托 Raj
Come on, Raj,
把袋子给我吧
give me a bag.
不行 不行 你都怀孕了
No, no, you're pregnant.
你只要安安心心
The only thing you carry
怀着我们未来的希望就好啦
is our hope for a better tomorrow.
嘿 你去哪里了?
Hey, where you been?
呃 Raj带我去看妇产科医生
Uh, Raj took me to the baby doctor
然后我们去逛了一会儿菜场
and then we swung by the grocery store.
你买饼干了吗?
Did you get graham crackers?
我说... 我... 胎儿还好吗?
I mean, are... what... is the baby okay?
买了 还好
Yes and yes.
我都不知道你今天需要帮忙啊
I didn't know you needed help running errands today.
本来是不需要 Raj主动要帮忙的
I didn't, but Raj volunteered.
真的?
Really?
是啊 你告诉他我怀孕了以后
Yeah, ever since you told him I was pregnant,
他一直对我的事很积极
he's really been making a fuss over me.
是嘛 他人真好
Oh. Well, I guess that's kind of sweet.
Bernie 我刚刚给你发了一份
Bernie, I just forwarded you a list
洛杉矶最好的五家哺乳顾问的表格
of the top five lactation consultants in Los Angeles.
我已经挑好了
I know my favorite,
不过我想听听你的意见
but I'd love to hear what you think.
现在感觉有点奇怪了
And it just got weird.
嘿 Amy到楼下了
Hey. Amy's downstairs.
好吧 等等
Okay, one sec.
呃 你... 你那是什么呀?
Uh, what... what you got goin' on here?
我买了一个棒球帽
I bought a baseball cap.
看出来了
I can see that.
是哪个队的?
What team did you get?
呃 是赫夫帕夫 哈利波特里的
Uh, Hufflepuff, from Harry Potter.
哎 反正我们在树林里
Well, we'll be in the woods.
我准备好了
I'm ready to go.
你有什么话要对他说吗?
Anything you'd like to say to him?
Sheldon 帽子不错
Nice hat, Sheldon.
谢谢
Thanks.
你干嘛对我那么刻薄啊?
Why are you so mean to me?
你在看什么啊?
What the hell are you watching?
Raj给我找了一些女人分娩的视频
Raj found all these childbirth videos online.
这一段是一个女人在河里生孩子
This one is of a woman giving birth in a river.
那是我这辈子见过的
Okay, that is the least Jewish thing
最不合犹太传统的事情
I've ever seen in my life.
有没有觉得Raj对这些孩子有关的事情
You feel like Raj is getting a little carried away
热情的太过分了?
with all the baby stuff?
没觉得
I don't think so.
他只是想参与进来
He just wants to be part of the experience.
好吧 如果你这么觉得的话
All right, if you say so.
盒子里是什么?
What's in the box?
是一个能让我们听见小孩心跳的
Oh, it's an ultrasonic microphone
超声波机器
so we can hear the baby's heartbeat.
噢
Oh.
不错啊
That's cool.
要不试试?
Can we try it?
事实上是Raj订购的
Actually, Raj ordered it.
他让我答应等他来了再试
He made me promise to wait till he was here.
这样他就能...
So he can be...
参与进来?
part of the experience?
是的
Yeah.
他允许我们怀孕的时候不叫上他还真让我意外呢
I'm surprised he let us conceive without him.
别哪壶不开提哪壶
It's a sore spot... don't bring it up.
这里真是空气清新又美好
It's so cute and rustic up here.
是啊
I know.
你看见他们还有一个租录像带的地方了吗?
Did you see they still have a video rental place?
看起来像威廉斯堡
it's like Colonial Williamsburg.
呃...
Well...
手机信号只有一格了
cell service is down to one bar,
如果有谁需要医疗护理
so if anyone needs medical attention
或是告诉陌生人他的政治观点蠢透了
or to tell a stranger their political views are stupid,
过了这个村就没这个店了
now's the time.
你有什么时候下线过吗?
Have you ever been off the grid before?
有过一次
Once.
我手机上的电池没电了
The battery ran out on my phone.
而iPAD又正在开机
I had to wait for my iPad to turn on.
我真怕他会吃了我
I was afraid he was gonna eat me.
Raj正在停车
Raj just pulled up.
我得跟他讲讲
I'm gonna say something to him.
随他吧 他是好意
Leave it alone. He means well.
你不觉得他应该克制一点吗?
So you don't think he needs to rein it in a little?
没觉得
No, not really.
你不在乎
And you're not concerned
他的做法就像你肚子里的是他的孩子一样?
he's acting like somehow this is his kid, too?
他只是支持我
He's just trying to be supportive.
只是支持你
Just supportive.
没觉得太过吗?
Not over-the-top in any way?
没有
No.
你们好
Hello!
你刚看见他搬这个进来了
You saw him carrying that.
在天上都能看见
Astronauts saw him carrying that.
地方不错呀!
This place is great!
那个医生让你住进来真太好了
So nice of that doctor to just let you use it.
她要带我去听蓝色少女音乐会
Well, she is taking me to an Indigo Girls concert,
有亏有赚
so hold that thought.
好吧
Okay.
呃
Well,
我们要不要检查一下对方身上的虱子?
should we check each other for ticks?
我们不过是从车里走过来而已
Sheldon, all we did was walk in from the car.
好吧 随你便
Oh. Well, suit yourself.
谁想检查一下我?
Who wants to check me?
其实吧 安全第一
On the other hand, safety first.
真的开始下雨了
Wow, it's really coming down.
真讨厌
This sucks.
野外徒步也去不了了
And there goes our hike.
噢 别啊!
Oh, not our hike!
现在我们必须
Now we have
呆在屋子里 安全又暖和
to stay safe and warm.
我们还是可以去的
You know, we could still go.
一点雨又杀不了你
A little rain isn't gonna kill us.
你跟Sheldon一起淋过雨吗?
Have you been outside in the rain with Sheldon?
- 没有  - 还不如死了呢
- No.  - You'll wish it would kill you.
那我们现在干什么?
So what do we do now?
那有桌牌游戏
They have some board games.
大部分叠叠乐的积木都不见了
Eh, most of the Jenga pieces are missing
拼字游戏的也只剩下七块了
and the Scrabble only has seven tiles,
如果你想拼个毫无技术含量的形状
so unless you want to build an unimpressive structure
摆在"SHNERPF"旁边 那你就去玩吧
with the word "SHNERPF" next to it, move on.
我们生一堆火吧
Hey, let's light a fire.
不错啊
Ooh, that sounds cozy.
我以前没生过火
I don't think I've lit a real fire before.
只是最基本的热力学
Ah, it's basic thermodynamics.
我们能搞定的
I'm sure we can figure that out.
我能把柴火堆成圆锥形利于空气流动
I could stack the logs conically to facilitate airflow.
那样能最大化氧气供给促进燃烧
That would maximize oxygen for optimal combustion.
对 所以我们只需要...
Right. So all we need is to...
搞定
Got it.
那是科学家的杰作
A scientist made that.
Raj 你是我在这个世界上最好的朋友
Look, Raj, you're my best friend in the world
我感谢你对孩子的热心
and I really appreciate your enthusiasm about the baby.
乐意效劳
Please, my pleasure.
Howie和我
And, of course, Howie and I
都想让你参与进来
both want you to be a part of all this.
但是我们还是有些界限的
But we have to set some boundaries.
我不明白
I don't understand.
不是我们三个人在生孩子
The three of us aren't having this baby.
是我们两个人的
Just the two of us.
噢...
Oh...
好吧 我明白了
Okay. Yeah, I get it.
我会冷静一些的
I'll back off.
感谢理解
Thanks for understanding.
当然了
Of course.
我会留给你们一些空间
I'll give you guys some space.
我还是把这个搬走吧
Let me just get this out of your way.
需要帮忙吗?
You need some help?
不用 我能搞定
No, I got it.
Raj... Raj 等等
Raj... Raj, wait.
Bernadette 拜托
Please, Bernadette.
让我带着尊严离开吧
Let me leave with my dignity.
嘿 你们想喝酒玩吗?
Hey, you guys want to play a drinking game?
好吧 那我们输定了
Oh, well now, well now, we'll never win.
你是酒场老手
You always play the drinking game.
不是喝酒 只是酒桌游戏
Not the drinking game, a drinking game.
说句公道话 两个你都很擅长呢
To be fair, good at both.
什么游戏?
What's the game?
好吧 名字叫做我从来没有
All right, it's called Never Have I Ever.
规则很简单
The rules are simple.
玩家说一件他们从来没干过的事
Someone says something they've never done,
其他人如果做过的话 就喝一口酒
but if you have done it, you take a drink.
我从来没玩过这游戏呢
I've never played that before.
嘿 等等
Hey, now, wait.
已经开始了 我需要喝一口吗?
Have we started? Do I drink?
- 现在什么情况?  - 好
- What is happening?  - Okay.
冷静一下 我先开始
Calm down. I'll go first.
好 让我想想
All right, let's see.
我从来没有...
Never have I ever...
她正在思考什么事
She's trying to think of something
她以前从来没干过
she's never done before.
这需要一点时间
This could take a while.
呵呵 有趣
Very funny.
好 我从来没有...
Okay, never have I ever...
嗯 你们造吗?
Yeah, you know what?
还是轮下一个人吧
Let's just circle back.
好 让我来
Okay, I'll go.
我从来没有被捕过
Never have I ever been arrested.
那我喝
So I drink.
不是 你干过才喝
No, it's only if you've done it.
明白了
Got it.
你竟然被捕过我不信
I can't believe you've been arrested.
我不相信Penny竟然没有
I can't believe Penny hasn't.
Sheldon 你做了什么?
Sheldon, what did you do?
不是什么值得骄傲的事
Well, I'm not proud of it,
但... 我横穿了马路
but... I jaywalked.
哦 简直像恐怖片
Oh, no, it's like a horror movie.
我们和一个疯子一起被困在了小屋里
We're trapped in a cabin with a maniac.
你那么做我真是太吃惊了
I'm surprised you would do that.
不 我横穿了马路
No, I crossed in the middle of the street.
正常来说 我是不会这么干的
And normally, I wouldn't,
但是我看到了一个面露凶相的女童军
but I saw an aggressive-looking Girl Scout,
而且那会儿还是饼干的热卖季节
and it was the heart of cookie season.
反正 当时还有一个警察
Anyway, there was a police officer,
他看到了整件事
and he witnessed the whole thing.
他因为... 因为什么逮捕你?
What... he arrested you for that?
他什么都没做
No, he didn't do anything.
所以我跟他说 "你难道没看到我横穿马路了吗
So I said, "You just saw me jaywalk.
你怎么不作为呢?"
Why aren't you doing your job?"
懂吗?
You know?
"或许我可以以
"M-Maybe I should arrest you
你冒充警察为由逮捕你"
for-for impersonating a police officer."
然后你就被捕了
And then you got arrested.
不然你以为呢
Oh, and how.
我觉得自己刚刚铸成了大错
I feel like I just made a horrible mistake.
是的
Yeah.
但是从另一方面来说
But on the other hand,
我也没有把他赶出我们的生活啊
I didn't kick him out of our lives.
我只是让他退后一点
I just asked him to back off a little.
是的
Yeah.
怎么了? 你要哭了吗?
What? Are you gonna cry?
是啊!
Yeah!
是因为孕激素还是真难过啊?
Is it baby hormones or actually sad?
我也不知道!
I can't tell anymore!
我去把他找回来
I'll go get him.
把熊熊也带回来!
And bring back the bear!
这游戏太危险了
This game's dangerous.
我能陷你于不利
I could get you in trouble.
是吗?
How?
嗯 我从来没有
Well, never have I ever
用Sheldon的牙刷清理过下水槽
used Sheldon's toothbrush to clean the sink.
好啊 你想这么玩是吗?
Fine, is that how you want to play this?
我从来没给我的
All right, never have I ever come up
生殖器起过名字
with a nickname for my own genitals.
我就不该把Alvin和Chipmunks的事告诉你
Never should've told you about Alvin and the Chipmunks.
好
Okay.
轮到我了
My turn.
嗯...
Um...
我从来没有
Never have I ever
在床上把女友干翻过
completely rocked my girlfriend's world in bed.
Amy啊...
Amy...
规则你们懂得
You know the rules.
喝吧
Drink.
嗯 喝吧
Yeah, go ahead.
没错就是这样
That's right.
好 轮到我了
All right, my turn.
嗯...
Mm...
哦 想到了
Oh, I know.
我从来没有因为觉得自己老婆不会管钱
Never have I ever kept a secret bank account,
而存过小金库
because I think my wife can't handle money.
我赢了吗?
Did I win?
感觉自己赢了呢
I feel like I won.
简直难以置信
I can't believe this.
我赚钱比你多这事你明白吗?
You realize I make more money than you?
我不是 我知道 但这也没什么大不了的
I don't, I know, but this isn't a big deal.
只是我存起来的一点点积蓄嘛
It's just a little savings I put aside.
我们结婚了
We're married.
我们应该无话不谈的
We're supposed to share everything.
什么 你指的是 你的巨额卡债吗?
What... you mean, like, your massive credit card debt?
我说了
I'm calling it.
我赢了
I won.
很感谢你的道歉
I appreciate the apology,
但是真没必要的
but it's really not necessary.
是我太过分了
I overstepped my bounds.
不 Raj 你做得很好
No, Raj, you've been great.
我只是 需要开始做自己该做的事了
I just, I need to start doing my part around here.
我听到了哟
I hear that.
那如果是这样的话
Well, if that's the case,
我能帮你做点什么吗?
is there anything I can do to help?
现在也没什么
Well, not right now.
但我们可以先试试你买的那个麦克风
But we could try out that microphone you got us,
一起听听宝宝的心跳
and listen to the baby's heartbeat.
真的吗?
Really?
我可以和你们一起听吗?
It's okay if I listen with you?!
当然了
Of course.
我可以在你肚子上抹凡士林吗？
Can I squirt the ultrasound jelly on your stomach?
呵呵 看啊
Hey, look at that.
一秒变尴尬
It's weird again.
好吧 你确实
Okay, you have
有权利生气
every right to be mad.
而且你说的没错
And what you said is true.
你确实比我挣得多
You do make more money than me.
我没有任何权利这么做
So I had no right to do what I did.
我很抱歉
And I'm so sorry.
希望你能原谅我
I hope you can forgive me.
你的小金库存了多久了?
How long have you had this secret account?
有几年了 但我只不过每个月存一点点
A couple years, but I just put a few bucks aside
以备不时之需罢了
every month for emergencies.
你已经存了多少了?
Well, how much you got in there?
6427刀了
$6,427.
还有47分是我过生日外婆给的红包
47 cent once my nana's birthday check gets here.
我的天啊 Leonard 你知道
My God, Leonard, do you know
我能用那种钱来做什么吗?
what I could do with that kind of money?
我当然知道 这就是我藏起来的原因
No, I do, and that's why I hid it.
如果你不用的话还有什么好处呢?
What good is it if you don't use it?
这么说吧 你有非常喜欢但从来不穿的鞋子
Uh, uh, you have shoes you love, but never wear.
我有我喜欢的钱
I have money I love,
但我不把它花掉
but never spend.
这个角度上说我们还是挺配的一对呢
We're kind of a cute couple that way.
但还是要说
Again,
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
我不该对你隐瞒的
I shouldn't have kept it a secret.
其实我也有自己的秘密没让你知道
Well, I have a secret I've been keeping from you, too.
是你的小金库吗?
Is it a secret bank account?
如果是的话就太完美了
Because that would be awesome.
我讨厌我的工作
I hate my job.
真的?
Really?
为什么?
Why?
因为我对为了销售
Because I don't feel good
和医生调情这种事很不爽
flirting with doctors for sales.
我是说 我知道这工作能挣很多钱
I mean, I know I make a lot of money.
但我已经很长时间不开心了
But I haven't been happy for a while.
你为什么不告诉我呢?
Why didn't you tell me?
因为我知道对你来说我有所成就是
Because I know how important it is to you
一件多么重要的事
that I'm having some success.
不是这样的
That's not true.
真的是这样吗? 所以你觉得我继续
Okay, really? So you'd be fine if I went
演戏和当女服务员也没什么大不了的?
back to acting and waiting tables again?
如果那是你想做的话 好啊
If that's what you want to do, yes.
那不是我想做的
Well, it's not what I want to do.
吓死宝宝了
Oh, yes.
我想不想什么的根本无所谓
Doesn't matter what I want.
这份工作能让我不做卡奴
Look, this job is gonna get me out of debt.
所以我要成熟一点坚持走下去
So I'm gonna do the grown-up thing and see it through.
你能这么想确实很成熟
Well, that is the grown-up thing.
我想是的
I guess.
我爱你
I love you.
我也爱你
I love you, too.
你知道吗
You know,
我从没有在外面下雨的时候
never have I ever made love
和别人在森林里野战过
in the forest while it was raining.
这个嘛 我得喝一杯
Well, guess I gotta drink.
好了 我们开始吧
All right, here we go.
我什么都没听到
I'm not hearing anything.
别着急呀
Well, give me a second.
你确定你行吗?
Are you sure you can do this?
嘿 别忘了是谁用他的金属探测器在
Hey, who found four dollars and change
沙滩上找到四美元和零钱的
on the beach with his metal detector?
是我埋在那里的 这样我们才能回家
I buried it there, so we could go home.
等等 找到了
Wait, that's it.
哇
Wow.
这是不是天底下最棒的了?
Isn't that the best?
你俩造了个人啊
You guys made a person.
是啊
We did.
我觉得这其中少不了我的帮助呢
And I like to think I helped.
没你啥事
You didn't.
让我想想
Oh, let me see.
想到了 我从来没有
Oh, um, never have I ever
喝过过期牛奶
drunk milk past its expiration date.
我从来没有
Never have I ever
取消过牙科诊所的预约
cancelled a dentist appointment.
我从来没有
Oh, uh, never have I ever
把我的脚放到海水里过
put my foot in the ocean.
我从来没有
Never have I ever
因为看到喜欢的东西而鸣笛
honked if I liked anything.
想到了!
Oh!
我从来没有
Uh... never have I ever
扔过 接过或者碰一下飞盘
thrown, caught or touched a Frisbee.
我从来没有
Never have I ever
在我尝之前
put salt on my food
先在食物上撒盐
without trying it first.
谁会啊...
Yeah...
这个好!
Oh!
我从来没有
Never have I ever
在电梯里面把所有键都按一遍
pushed all the buttons in an elevator.
谁没有段黑历史啊
Well, we all have a past.